This is Berk.
So far off the map
that it might as well not exist.
My village
in a word: sturdy.
It's been here for generations
but every single building is new.
The air is crisp, the water is clean
and the views are
nothing to complain about.
The only downsides are the pests.
You see, most places have
mice or mosquitoes.
We have...
Dragons.
Most people would leave.
Not us.
We're Vikings.
We don't run from fights.
We start them.
- Hey! Hiccup!
- Evening!
- Go home!
- I will just as soon as I...
You're in the way again!
Hiccup, play dead!
You see, dragons have been
a bit of a problem.
Here and, well, everywhere.
So we decided
to take the fight to them.
How's that working out for us?
What are you doing?
What is he doing out again?
Get inside. Go on.
That's Stoick the Vast
chief of the tribe.
They say when he was a baby
he popped a dragon's head
clean off its shoulders.
Do I believe it?
- Yes, I do.
- What have we got?
Gronckles, Nadders,
Zipplebacks, Skrills.
Snorti spotted a Monstrous Nightmare.
Any Night Furies?
None so far, Chief.
Good.
- Follow me.
- Right, Chief.
Come on, you wretches!
You heard him. Come on, lads.
Oh. Out again?
Just pretend I'm not even here.
I'll be in and out
before you can say...
Not so fast.
Come on, please.
The meathead with attitude
and interchangeable hands is Gobber.
Here. Go on.
I've been his apprentice
ever since I was little.
I'm keeping my eye on you.
I'm not even supposed to be out here.
Since when did that ever stop ya?
- Guard the food stores.
- Aye, Chief.
- Protect the livestock.
- Aye, Stoick.
And keep an ear out for Night Furies.
Hammer.
Fire brigade!
Ah, the fire brigade.
Berk's cool kids.
They get to be out in the action.
Guys, out of the way!
But they're nothing
without their captain
the shining star of our generation.
Amazing without even trying.
The one that smokes them all.
Astrid.
What?
Shouldn't you be in bed?
Come on, back to work.
You know, I need to get out there.
Show my stuff, make my mark.
You've made plenty of marks,
all in the wrong places.
Give me two minutes.
I'll take down a dragon.
My life will get infinitely better.
I might even get a girlfriend.
There's a Zippleback behind you!
Astrid?
But she's a real Viking.
You can't wield a hammer.
You can't swing an axe.
You can't even throw one of these.
See, but this,
this will throw it for me.
- Another one.
- It's fully redesigned. It's...
It's...
double-barreled.
You see, this right here
- this is what I'm talking about.
- Okay, this is a mild cal...
mild calibration issue.
If you ever want to get out there
and start fighting dragons
you've gotta stop all of...
all of this.
You just gestured to all of me.
Yeah. Stop being all of you.
Oh, yeah.
You, sir, are playing
a dangerous game
keeping this contained?
There will be consequences.
Well, I will take my chances.
Sword, sharpen. Now.
One day, I'll get out there.
Because killing a dragon
is everything around here.
Gronckles are tough.
Taking one down
would at least get me noticed.
A Zippleback?
Exotic, exciting.
Two heads, twice the status.
Lopping off a Nadder's head
would definitely show them I belong.
Come on, lads!
They found the sheep.
Then let loose
with everything we've got.
Chief!
And then there's
the Monstrous Nightmare.
Reload!
Only the best Vikings go after those.
But the ultimate prize
is the dragon that
no one has ever seen.
- We call it the...
- Night Fury!
Jump!
And we've got a Night Fury.
Never steals food.
Never shows itself.
And never misses.
Time for old Gobber to take over.
Stay put here.
Here. I'm serious.
No one has ever killed a Night Fury.
Attack!
That's why I'm going to be the first.
You again? Get back inside!
- I'll make a point of it.
- Gonna get yourself killed, Hiccup!
I know! Sorry.
Gobber!
Here, give me that.
Mind yourself!
This Nadder still has
some fire in it.
Come on.
Give me something to shoot at.
Come on, show yourself.
I hit it.
I hit it!
Did anybody see that?
Except for you.
Oh, Gods.
Spitelout, do not let that escape.
Thanks a lot.
You're all out.
Let's see what else you're made of.
Aye, that's what I thought.
Oh, and there's
one more thing to know.
Look out!
Sorry, Dad.
Watch out!
Okay, but I hit a Night Fury.
Dad, this isn't like any other time.
I mean, I really hit one.
Aye, a dragon no one's ever seen.
Because it uses night
as its camouflage.
If you squint, you can see
it blotting out the stars.
That's how I shot it down.
Stop!
Stop.
Every time you step outside,
disaster happens.
Can you not see
that I have bigger problems?
Winter is almost here
and I have an entire village to feed.
Between you and me, the village
could do with a little less feeding.
This isn't a joke, Hiccup!
Why can't you follow
the simplest orders?
Because I can't stop myself.
Okay? I see a dragon,
and I have to just kill it.
You know, it's who I am.
You are many things, son
but a dragon killer
is not one of them.
Get back to the house.
Make sure he stays there.
How much can one person mess up?
Anyone else would have been
booted off the island by now.
I guess being son of the chief
has its privileges.
If not for the chief, though...
Anyway, my dad's
super proud of me, so...
- Dad, I was just talking...
- Don't talk to me in public.
You know, I really did hit one.
Course you did, Hiccup.
He never listens.
Well, that runs in the family.
And when he does
it's always
with some disappointed scowl
like somebody forgot
the meat in the stew.
I've seen that look.
Oi. You're thinking
about this all wrong, eh.
It's not so much what you look like.
It's what's inside of you
he can't stand.
Thank you for summing that up.
W... Wait. The point is
stop trying so hard
to be something you're not.
I just wanna be one of you guys.
I know you do.
No one said it would be easy!
But may I remind you
we are all descendants
of the finest dragon fighters
from everywhere Vikings have traveled
who gathered here because they knew
that we were within spitting distance
of a key dragon's nest.
If we can just take it
we can wipe out the devils for good.
Take it?
- We can't even find it.
- Exactly.
This nest is starting to sound
more and more like a fairy tale.
We're exhausted.
And what do we have
to show for it, eh?
- Nothing!
- We have purpose.
Oh, come on.
We are the warriors of Berk
the roughest, toughest tribe
this side of the sun.
No?
Phlegma.
We watched you take down
a Zippleback single-handedly.
I mean, sure, you lost
your leg in the process
but you came out on top, didn't you?
- Well...
- Yes, you did.
Retcha, your people came
from the Far East.
Fungi, yours all the way
from... from the Silk Road.
Loogi, your people came
from the sunbaked coasts of Bláland.
And look at us.
We're still here.
We're still fighting.
We're still watching
each other's backs.
So are we really gonna
pack up and go home
while these bloody beasts are
still a threat to all of our lands?
Is that who we are?
No.
- Is it?
- No!
Is it?
No, Chief, I guess not.
That's what I thought.
Elder Gothi
give us a sign.
Do we stand a chance of finding
the nest before the ice sets in?
Then that's all I need.
Back into the fog we go.
All right, everyone.
Prepare the ships!
Let's go!
Do I take my bucket hand
for when they burn our ships
or my swimming hand
for when they sink them?
Not so fast, Gobber.
I don't have time
to train this year's recruits
so you'll do it.
The old rite of passage.
Hiccup's just come of age, hasn't he?
I meant the others.
Yeah, so while I'm busy,
he'll cover the stall.
Molten steel, razor-sharp blades
lots of time on his hands.
What could possibly go wrong?
What am I gonna do with him, Gobber?
Stick him in training.
No. I'm serious.
Yeah, so am I.
The kid wants this
more than anything.
Believe it or not
that young man actually wants
to make you proud.
But he's got a mind of his own.
Gets that from his mother.
Look what happened to her.
Yeah, 'cause Valka was
the stubborn one.
- See, when I was a boy,
- Oh, here we go.
I... I followed orders.
Right? I worked hard.
Because I believed
in what a... a Viking could do.
Crush mountains
level forests, tame seas.
I knew what I was
and what I had to become.
Hiccup is...
He's not that boy.
What chance does he have
of following in my footsteps?
Yeah.
You can't stop him, Stoick.
You can only prepare him.
Because the truth is
we aren't always gonna
be around to protect him.
He's gonna get out there again.
He's probably out there now.
How could I lose an entire dragon?
I did it.
I did it!
Why couldn't you have been dead?
Now I have to kill you.
Hiccup?
Dad.
Look, I need to talk to you, Dad.
I need to speak with you, too, son.
- I've decided I don't want
- I think it's time you learn
- to fight dragons.
- What?
- Well, you go first.
- No... no. You... You go first.
You get your wish.
Dragon Training.
Start in the morning.
Oh, man, I really
should've gone first.
You know, 'cause I was thinking
we have a surplus
of dragon-fighting Vikings
but do we have
enough bread-making Vikings
- or...
- You'll need this.
Dad...
I don't wanna fight dragons.
Come on. Yes, you do.
No, let me rephrase.
I can't kill dragons.
But you will.
No, I'm very extra sure that I won't.
It's time, Hiccup.
Can you not hear me?
The Trial of Flame is
where Vikings are made
where heroes are forged
where future chiefs are born.
I'm none of those things.
I'm not like you, Dad.
Listen.
When you carry this axe
you carry all of us with you
which means you walk like us
you talk like us, you think like us.
No more of this.
You just gestured to all of me.
Deal?
This conversation is feeling
- very one-sided.
- Deal?
Deal.
Good.
Train hard.
I'll be back.
Probably.
And I'll be here.
Maybe.
Welcome to the Trial of Flame.
The moment
we've all been waiting for.
I just got to pick
a spot for my statue.
It's so much bigger from down here.
Can you guys believe
we're actually standing here?
This is where Chief Greybile slew
the Whispering Death.
Yeah, and it's where Chief Tuffnut
will slay everything else.
- Watch and learn.
- Man, I can't wait
to get some legendary war wounds.
Yeah, like a nasty gash
right across my face.
- Call me boring...
- Boring.
but I'm just excited to see
some real live dragons up close.
You know, I could do
without the permanent injuries and...
Oh, where's the glory in that?
Yeah, it's only fun
if you get a scar out of it.
I know, right?
Pain. Love it.
Oh, great. Who let him in?
I guess Daddy pulled
some strings, huh?
Aren't you two, like,
a little old to be here?
- Ouch.
- Wait
- what'd you say, whippersnapper?
- What'd you say? Say it again!
Yeah, touchy subject.
They've flunked Dragon Training
a few times.
It was four times, actually.
Yeah, and it's called
being held back.
As in too valuable to let go of.
Real sensitive, Hiccup.
Nice name, by the way.
Your name is Snotlout.
Exactly.
It's a manly Viking name.
Translates from the ancient texts
as "one who beateth the snot
- out of a--"
- Shut up.
Let's get started.
Bloody kids.
You are now the latest to join
this time-honored tradition.
Every toe biter born into our tribe
must one day survive this arena
if they ever hope to do battle
alongside the rest of us.
It will be grueling.
And it will be very, very dangerous.
But whoever does best
will win the title of Top Slayer.
And with it...
And with it, the honor
of killing their first dragon
in front of the entire village.
There is no greater glory.
What?
Hiccup already killed a Night Fury
so does that, like, what,
disqualify him or...
Oh, ignore him.
You're skinny.
You're weak.
That'll make you less of a target.
They'll see you as slim pickings.
Not worth the effort.
They'll go after the more...
Viking-like teens instead.
Behind these doors
are just a few of the many species
you will learn to fight.
The Deadly Nadder.
Attack, eight, armor, 16.
The Hideous Zippleback.
Plus 11 stealth, times two.
The Monstrous Nightmare.
- Firepower, 15.
- The Terrible Terror.
- Attack, eight, venom, 12!
- Will you stop that?
You big bag of wool.
And finally, the gruesome Gronckle.
Jaw strength, eight.
Hey, big guy!
Aren't you gonna, like,
teach us something first?
I believe in learning on the job!
Today is all about defense!
If you get blasted, you're out!
Or, you know, dead.
So, what's the first thing
you're gonna need?
- A shield!
- Shield, yes. Go!
- Out of my way.
- That one's mine!
Shield is your most
important piece of equipment.
If you have to choose
between a weapon and a shield...
Just put it down.
Take the shield.
- Give it! Find your own shield!
- Mine, mine, mine!
Ruffnut, Tuffnut, you're out.
Shields are good
for another thing: noise.
Make plenty of it
to throw off the dragon's aim.
Remember, all dragons have
a limited number of blasts.
How many does a Gronckle have?
- Six!
- Six, yes.
That's one for each of ya.
Although, interesting tidbit
rocks from different regions
vary in mineral comp--
What are you do...
What are you doing?
What are you doing? Get in there!
Fishlegs, you're out.
- Four shots left.
- Yeah.
We're pretty much gonna be
the stars of this thing.
Almost like we were meant
to be together.
It's an elimination game, genius.
There's only one Top Slayer.
Snotlout, you're done.
Three shots.
Looks like it's just you and me, huh?
Nope. Just me.
Hey! Eyes on me!
Yes.
Well done, Astrid.
Two shots left.
Oh, come on.
Hiccup, you're out.
- One shot left.
- Hey, watch it!
Hiccup!
End of lesson.
Back to bed, you overgrown sausage.
Remember, a dragon
will always, always...
go for the kill.
So, why didn't you?
Okay.
Let's review, shall we?
Where did Astrid go wrong
in the ring today?
I mistimed my somersault dive.
It was sloppy.
It threw off my reverse tumble.
- Yeah. We noticed.
- Hey.
Back off my girl.
All right? She's trying her best.
Yeah. Don't beat yourself up.
You'll get it.
Just follow my lead next time!
Astrid's right.
You've gotta be tough on yourselves.
All it takes is one weak link.
You made it, then?
You gotta start taking this seriously
because we are living
in a battleground.
And in case you haven't noticed,
the other side is winning.
You're gonna need
every advantage you can get.
So, if you haven't done your homework
allow me to present to you...
The Book of Dragons.
Everything we know
about every dragon we know of.
Each of your tribes brought
their wisdom and experience
to these pages.
It's our most hallowed possession.
No dragon raids tonight
so study up.
You mean read?
I've read it like a hundred times.
There's a Scauldron that sprays
your face with boiling water.
And then there's another...
Why would I read words
when I can just kill the stuff
the words tell me stuff about?
Right? I mean, like,
I'm the kind of guy
that other guys write
word books about.
Boys!
Don't worry, though. I'm here
for all of your dragon-related
inquiries, okay?
Theories, stats.
I've even made cards...
You can ask me anything.
- Stop following me.
- Here.
How about now? Try me now.
Absolutely not.
So...
sounds like a gruesome,
grisly, good time, huh?
- Read it.
- You know...
maybe they're not as bad
as we think they are.
Are you actually insane,
or do you just act that way?
Is there... Is there a third option?
Wiping out dragons is why we're here.
It's why the best of our tribes
came together.
Because yes, dragons
are as bad as we think.
Yeah, I know. I'm just saying
maybe we're part of the problem.
You know, moving in on their lands
eating their food.
Wow.
You live in a different world,
don't you?
- What?
- Just coast by
taking it all for granted.
- Well, I don't think that...
- Never having to work for anything
never struggling to get a foot up.
Well, guess what?
I come from nothing.
No chief for a dad,
no handouts, no excuses.
I'm not afraid of hard work.
I'm willing to do
whatever it takes
to get the job done
which, in this case, means
wiping out the dragons
for the good of everyone.
Yeah.
You know what else?
I'm... I'm afraid... afraid to ask.
I've got my eye
on that big house of yours.
I'm gonna be chief one day.
I... I don't doubt it.
Actually, I think
my dad would be thrilled.
Besides, you're the kid
he always hoped for.
Instead, he got...
all this.
Stay out of my way, Hiccup.
"Dragon classifications."
"Strike class.
Fear class. Mystery class."
"Thunderdrum.
When startled, the Thunderdrum
produces a concussive sound
that can kill a man at close range.
Extremely dangerous. Kill on sight.
Timberjack.
Skrill. Whispering Death.
Burns its victims.
Buries its victims.
Chokes its victims.
Turns its victims inside out.
Extremely dangerous.
Kill on sight.
Kill on sight. Kill on sight."
"Night Fury.
Size: unknown. Speed: unknown.
The unholy offspring
of lightning and death itself.
Never engage this dragon."
I can almost smell them.
Take us in...
to Helheim's Gate.
Here we go again.
Hard to port!
Set the oars! Furl the sails!
All together.
Higher! Pull!
We're not alone!
- Look up!
- Watch your heads!
Turn back!
They're everywhere!
Hey, I just...
I just happened to notice
that the book had
nothing on Night Furies.
Is there maybe, like...
like, another book?
Maybe, like, a Night Fury pamph--
Focus, Hiccup.
You're not even trying.
Today is about attack.
Nadders are quick
and light on their feet.
Your job is to be
quicker and lighter.
Sorry!
I'm really beginning to question
your teaching methods!
Look for its blind spot.
Every dragon has one.
Find it, hide in it, then strike.
Do you ever bathe?
If you don't like it,
go find your own blind spot. Go!
Blind spot, yes.
Deaf spot, not so much.
I am hurt. I am very much hurt.
So, how does one sneak up
on a Night Fury?
No one has ever met one
and lived to tell the tale.
Now, get in there!
Yeah, I know. I'm just saying, like
- how would--
- Hiccup.
Down.
Save yourself!
I'll take care of this.
Not my fault, Astrid.
I got distracted
by the light in your eyes!
Wait! Just let me...
Yes. Well done, Astrid.
Nothing like giving them
a taste of their own medicine, eh?
Also, "Well done, Snotlout,
with the assist,"
right? What a team!
Is anyone taking this seriously?
Take it seriously.
'Cause in case you forgot
our parents' war is
about to become ours!
Figure out which side you're on.
Toothless.
I could've sworn you had...
teeth.
I... I don't have any more.
Thanks?
Oh, come on. You're kidding, right?
And then he turned and grabbed me arm
and with one twist
he took my hand clean off
and he swallowed it whole.
Yeah, he must have spread
the word around
'cause within a month,
another one had taken my leg.
Probably a Skrill.
Serrated teeth, jaw strength 17.
I'll avenge
your fallen limbs, big guy.
I'll chop off the hands and feet
of every dragon that I see.
Nah.
It's the wings and the tail you want.
If they can't fly,
they can't get away.
A downed dragon is a dead dragon.
Anyone can get by
without the other bits.
I'm gonna lose all of my limbs.
I volunteer Ruffnut
to lose at least one limb.
What?
We're twins. Your pain is my pain.
You're twins?
Even our own mother
can't tell us apart.
It's uncanny.
There we go.
Astrid's got the right idea.
Get your sleep while you can.
Soon, Stoick will be back.
And one of you will be chosen
to kill the dragon.
Question is, who?
Toothless!
Brought breakfast.
What do you think, bud?
Okay.
We got some cod...
some salmon
and a whole smoked eel.
No eel! Scratch the eel!
Yeah, I... can't say
I love it, either.
That's it.
Stick to the good stuff.
I'll just be back here...
minding my own business.
Okay.
Okay. Not bad.
It could work.
If it's... Whoa! Okay!
Toothless, no! Oh, Gods!
Toothless! Oh, Gods!
It's working!
Yeah!
Today is all about teamwork.
If you work together,
you might just survive.
You see, a wet dragon head
cannot light its fire.
But a Hideous Zippleback
is extra tricky
'cause one head breathes gas
and the other head lights it.
Your job is to know which is which.
Good luck.
Razor-sharp fangs that inject
venom for predigestion.
Prefers to keep its victims...
conscious.
You know, I'm kind of glad
we got partnered.
Us girls got to stick together.
- Until I have to take you out.
- Shush.
I think
I've pretty much won Astrid over.
I mean, she can barely
even look at me.
You came to the right man for advice.
- I didn't ask--
- If there's one thing
the Viking girl brain
can't resist, it's...
Look out!
- Hey!
- It's us, geniuses.
Lightning reflexes.
I see hideous heads, I strike.
Ow.
Make that one hideous head, Astrid.
Save yourselves!
Also known to toy with its victims
dismembering them limb from limb.
Will you please stop that?
Fishlegs!
Wrong head.
Get out of there, Hiccup!
Oh, come on.
Yeah. Back!
Run... Hiccup.
Don't make me tell you again! Yeah.
Yeah, that's right. Back in your pen.
Now, think about what you've done.
So, are we done today?
Just because I have
some things I need to...
Yeah, I'm gonna...
I'm gonna see you guys tomorrow.
Hey.
Oh, come on.
Just try it!
I'm gonna die!
No!
No, please!
Just kind of angle yourself!
No!
Oh, come on!
- Out of my way.
- Move... move!
Watch yourselves.
Get in its blind spot.
I got it! It's mine!
No, don't bring it over here!
Little guy. What is his name again?
- I don't remember.
- Hey. Slow down.
- Are you trying to show us up?
- No.
I've never seen someone
take down a Gronckle like that.
I mean, I do it all the time,
but how did you learn?
Learn what? What exactly was that?
Okay, see, I'd love to explain.
It's just, I left my axe
back in... in the ring.
Who's a good boy? Who's a good boy?
Okay.
Yeah, yeah? You itchy?
Is that the spot?
Hiccup.
Yo, there he is.
Hey, Hiccup.
- Okay.
- Hiccup. Wait.
- I have a proper question.
- So I'm thinking that...
All it needs to be is
you and me in the ring.
A Terrible Terror!
It's like the size of my...
Get it off... get it off!
And the other ships?
Dad!
I got it.
I missed you.
In, like, a super manly way.
I got so much to tell you
about the Trial of Flame.
It's basically between... Dad?
Dad?
Da... Okay, I'll see you at home!
So, no nest, then?
Not even close.
I hope you had more success.
Well, if by success, you mean
your parenting troubles are over
then yeah.
Did you hear the news, Chief?
Everyone is so relieved.
Good riddance to old Hiccup.
Aye. No one will miss that nuisance.
Hiccup is...
gone?
Yeah. Yeah, most afternoons,
but who can blame him?
The life of a celebrity
can be very rough.
He can barely walk
through the village
without being swarmed
by his army of new fans.
Who would've thought he has this...
way with the beasts?
All right, bud.
We're gonna take this nice and slow.
Here we go.
Position three.
No, four.
You ready?
Come on. Come on.
Yeah, look at us!
My fault. My fault.
Yeah, yeah, I'm on it.
Position five.
Come on, bud.
Yeah. Go, baby!
Oh, this is amazing!
The wind in my...
Cheat sheet!
Stop!
Oh, Gods!
Yeah!
- Son!
- Dad! You're back.
Okay, Gobber's not here
- so...
- I know.
Came looking for you.
You... You did? Why?
You've been keeping secrets.
I have?
Just how long did you think
you could hide it from me?
I... I don't even know
what you're talking...
Nothing happens on this island
without me hearing about it.
So, let's talk about that dragon.
Oh, Gods, Dad.
I'm... I'm so sorry.
I... I was gonna tell you sooner.
I just didn't know...
You're not upset?
What? What?
I was hoping for this.
- You were?
- Oh, yes.
And believe me, it only gets better.
Just wait till you spill
a Nadder's guts for the first time.
Or... Or mount your first
Gronckle head on a spear.
What a feeling.
You really had me going there, son.
All those years of the worst Viking
Berk has ever seen.
Odin, it was rough.
I almost gave up on you.
And all the while,
you were holding out on me.
Thor almighty.
Who would have thought that
Dragon Training would have been
your place to shine, huh?
You might even win Top Slayer.
Just like your old man.
Who knows?
You know, actually,
with you doing so well in the ring...
- I'm gonna... Okay.
- Sit.
We finally have
something to talk about.
So, I...
Oh. Oh, I...
I brought you something...
to...
keep you safe in the ring.
Your mother would've
wanted you to have it.
Wow. Thanks.
It's half of her breastplate.
Matching set.
Keeps her...
It keeps her close, you know?
Wear it proudly, son.
You've held up your end of the deal.
- Yeah.
- Yeah. Tired.
- Yeah, I'm gonna get some sleep.
- Good talk.
- Big day tomorrow.
- Yeah. Just... The Trial of Flame
- and it takes a lot out of you.
- Yeah, Trial of Flames... Flame.
- Good luck with that.
- Yeah, thank you, thank you
- I hope you like the...
- for the... the breast hat.
- hat. Yeah.
- Yeah.
Okay, well, good night.
No more of your tricks.
I'm taking Top Slayer today.
Yeah, yeah, okay. It's all yours.
Top... Top Slay away.
Sorry.
Last chance. Make it count.
Come on!
Go on, Astrid!
- You got it! Go on!
- Come on, Hiccup!
Come on!
No!
Son of a half-troll, rat-eating...
Glad to see
she's handling it gracefully.
You!
Okay.
- Later.
- Hey, hey. Not so fast.
No, I can't. I'm gonna be late for...
What? Late for what, exactly?
- Another year,
- Shut up.
and another Trial of Flame
has come to an end.
Elder Gothi has made her decision.
The new Top Slayer will be...
Hiccup?
You've done it, Hiccup.
You won the Trial of Flame.
You get to kill the dragon!
That's my boy!
Hiccup, you won!
Yeah.
Hooray me.
I can't wait to...
Beat it and never come back.
All right, bud. Time's up.
My thoughts exactly.
What are you...
What are you doing here?
Looking for answers.
Who's bud? Your trainer?
Did he dress you up in this?
I know this looks suspicious
but funnily enough, I...
You're right! You're right. I...
I'm through with the lies.
I've been making outfits
so you got me.
It's time everybody knew.
Just take me back.
Why would you do that?
That's for the lies.
And that's for everything else.
Oh, no.
Run. Run!
- No! No.
- What...
Toothless, no! Stop. It's okay.
She's a friend. She's a friend.
Toothless, Astrid. Astrid, Toothless.
The...
The Night Fury.
I wouldn't.
We're dead.
Hey. Where do you think you're going?
Hiccup! Get me down from here!
You have to give me
a chance to explain.
I'm not listening
to anything you have to say.
Then I won't speak.
Just let us show you.
Please, Astrid.
What is this?
It's my design.
Yeah. Pretty much the co-captain.
Then let's get this over with.
You got it.
Toothless, let's take her down.
Gently.
Nothing to be afraid of.
Oh, nice touch!
I thought you were his co-captain!
I am! It's a temporary
dragon malfunction!
We worked out
a whole system, remember?
If we survive, I'm gonna kill you!
And now the spinning!
Thank you for nothing,
you useless reptile.
Please just make it stop.
I'm clearly not the one in control!
Then I'm sorry!
Toothless, I'm sorry!
Fine.
You made your point.
It doesn't change the fact
you have to kill one tomorrow.
But if we can change your mind...
What?
You gonna take everyone up
for a magical ride?
It won't erase
what they've done to us, Hiccup.
They hunt us, steal our food.
And one of them took my mom.
But do we just keep
killing one another?
As opposed to...
I don't know.
But you botched our escape plan,
so I'm gonna need a minute.
Well, I might not snitch on you.
And we might not drop you in the sea.
Bud? What's up?
What is it?
Hey. Hey.
Get down!
Toothless, get us out of here.
It looks like
they're hauling in their kill.
Then what does that make us?
The dragons' nest.
Oh, what my dad wouldn't give
to find this.
What is that?
All right, bud, time to go.
I can't believe it took
this long to figure it out.
It all makes sense now.
It's like a giant beehive.
They're the workers,
and that's their queen.
Their alpha.
It controls them.
We gotta find your dad.
No, no, no, not yet.
They'll...
They'll kill Toothless.
Astrid
we have to think
this through carefully.
Hiccup, we just discovered
the dragons' nest
and you want to keep it a secret?
To protect your pet dragon?
Are you serious?
Yes.
Okay.
Then what do we do?
Just give me until tomorrow.
I'll figure it out.
That's for kidnapping me.
Hey, are you gonna...
And that's for everything else.
What?
Well, I can finally show
my face in public again!
All right.
If someone had told me
that in a few short weeks
Hiccup would've gone
from being, well, Hiccup...
to placing first
in the Trial of Flame
I mean, I would've tied them
to a mast and shipped them off
for fear they'd gone mad.
And you know it.
But here we are.
My son has won
the title of Top Slayer.
No one is more surprised...
or more proud than I am.
Today, my boy becomes a warrior.
Today, he becomes one of us!
Yeah!
Hiccup!
Watch out for that dragon.
It's not the dragon
I'm worried about.
Look
I'm gonna try
to put an end to all this
but if something goes wrong
in there, just...
don't get involved.
My dad respects you too much.
Yeah.
But...
you have something I don't.
Something none of us have.
So...
I'm going to stand by you...
come what may.
Come what may.
It's time, Hiccup.
Knock him dead, son.
Hiccup!
Go, Hiccup!
Show 'em everything I taught you!
Should've been me.
All right?
Good crowd, isn't it?
Hiccup!
I would have gone with the hammer.
Just... Just give him a chance.
I'm ready.
What is he doing?
I'm not gonna hurt you.
I'm not one of them.
Stop the fight.
No.
You all need to see this.
They're not what we think they are.
We don't have to kill them.
I said stop the fight!
Out of my way!
Get out of there, Hiccup!
Hiccup!
No!
- Quick, quick! Grab his hand!
- Climb up!
- Hiccup, grab my hand!
- Get over here!
Get over here, man!
Just grab his hand!
Astrid, get back here!
That's an order!
Run!
Come on!
Hiccup!
Night Fury.
Night Fury!
He's real!
All right, bud. Go on. Go.
Go, go! Get to the side of him!
Get out of the way, Hiccup!
No, stop.
You're only making it worse!
Astrid!
I got it. Go!
Stoick, he won't hurt you.
Get around it!
No!
Toothless!
Don't.
Take it down!
Grab its legs!
- Hold it down!
- No! No, don't hurt him!
Stay back!
And you.
Put it with the others.
- I should have known!
- Dad.
- I should have seen the signs.
- Dad!
- We had a deal!
- I know, but that was before...
It's all so messed up.
So everything in the ring,
what, a trick? A lie?
No, I should have told you
before now.
Take that out on me, it's my fault
but please don't hurt Toothless.
The dragon?
That's what you're worried about?
Not the people you almost killed?
He's not dangerous.
He was protecting me.
They took your mother,
for Gods' sake!
If she could see you now
standing there with them
when they've killed hundreds of us.
And we've killed thousands of them!
They defend themselves. That's all.
They raid us because they have to.
If they don't bring enough food back
they'll be eaten themselves!
There's something else
on their island.
A dragon like I've never seen.
Their island?
You've been to the nest.
Did I say nest?
How did you find it?
I didn't. Toothless did.
Only a dragon can find the island.
No. Dad, no.
You don't know
what you're up against.
This is nothing like
you've ever seen.
You can't win this one!
For once in your life,
would you please just listen to me?
You've thrown your lot in with them.
You're not one of us.
You're not my son.
Ready the ships!
We sail at dawn!
Dragon to the port side!
Forward on the leading line!
Swing it out slightly!
Here she comes! Easy!
Careful with the head.
- One more.
- Oh, careful now.
- Hey.
- Weapons loaded!
Spare rigging aboard?
- Aye.
- Hoist the sails!
Aye, Chief.
- Ready the oars.
- Aye, Stoick.
We set sail for Helheim's Gate!
Lead us home, devil.
I tried to stop them.
I ended up giving them
exactly what they wanted.
I should've just...
I should've killed him
when I found him in those woods.
It would have been
better for everyone.
Yeah.
The rest of us would have done it.
So, why didn't you?
- Why didn't you?
- I don't know.
- I couldn't.
- That's not an answer.
Why is this so important
to you all of a sudden?
Because I want to remember
what you say right now.
For the love of...
Because I was weak.
Because I was a coward,
because I wouldn't kill a dragon.
- You said "wouldn't" that time.
- Whatever! I wouldn't!
I'm the first Viking
in who knows how long
who wouldn't kill a dragon.
First to ride one, though.
So?
I wouldn't kill him because...
he looked
just as frightened as I was.
When I looked at him...
I saw myself.
Bet he's really frightened now.
What are you gonna do about it?
Probably something stupid.
Well, you've already done that.
Then something crazy.
That's more like it.
Sound your positions.
Stay within earshot.
One length to your stern.
On your starboard flank.
Why aren't they attacking?
Maybe they know something we don't.
Are you just a glutton
for punishment or what?
We have a fighting chance this time.
Thanks to Hiccup.
How long do you think we're gonna--
Step aside, Drül.
- Ship the oars!
- Oars in.
Okay, wait.
You just disgraced yourself
in front of the whole village.
- Why would we listen to you?
- 'Cause I said so.
Exactly. Pay attention, gang.
Look, my dad means well,
but he's stubborn.
And he's about to be way in
over his head, so it's up to us.
Us?
I can't pull this off
without you guys.
And you all have
something special to offer.
Say no more.
You were wise to seek
the world's most deadly weapon.
- It's me.
- You've got a wild side
and I like it.
Astrid, you're our strongest fighter.
We need you to lead us.
Lead us where exactly?
They left with every ship we have.
Stick with me.
That's where that went.
Stay low.
Be ready.
We're here.
No.
Hiccup, I...
Relax.
It's okay.
Where are you going?
You're gonna need something
to help you hold on.
Get ready.
It's gonna be a long night.
Form a defensive line.
Sharpen those axes, lads!
It's not even.
Chief.
Ready, Chief.
- Stand strong.
- Aye, Stoick.
Make your people proud.
We will, Stoick.
Today, we destroy
the reign of the dragon
once and for all.
However this ends,
it ends right here, right now!
So let's send these devils
back to hell!
Is that it?
The nest is ours!
This isn't over.
Get clear!
Fall back!
Fall back! Everyone, fall back!
Retreat!
Get to the ships!
No!
Get them
to the far side of the island!
Aye, Chief. Let's move!
This way! All of you!
- Get out of here, lads!
- Follow me!
Gobber, go with the others.
Why? Where are you going?
Actually, I'm gonna stick around.
You've got
that wild look in your eye.
I can buy them some time
if I give that thing
something to hunt.
And I can double that time.
I know. I'm a big softy.
Softest part of you is your teeth.
Remember, that thing is their queen.
They're inclined
to do whatever it says.
We've gotta help them fight back.
Fishlegs, what do we got?
Heavily armored skull and tail
perfect for bashing and crushing.
Small eyes, large nostrils.
Relies on hearing and smell.
Got it. Astrid.
Okay. Snotlout, Fishlegs,
hang in its blind spot.
Make some noise. Keep it confused.
Ruff, Tuff, figure out
its shot limit.
Make it mad.
That's our specialty!
Try not to get killed, guys!
This thing doesn't have a blind spot.
There!
Hey, bud.
I'm... I'm good.
Be careful.
I know, I know,
but I'm... I'm here now.
Keep hammering!
But we're confusing our own dragons!
Oh, no!
This way! This way! Come on! Come on!
Guys, keep moving! Keep moving!
- Come on!
- Go!
Is that my kid?
- Snotlout!
- Come on! Throw it!
Whoa, girl.
Going down!
I'm okay.
Less okay.
I got you, Fishlegs!
What's wrong?
Got something in your eye?
Yeah! Now, that's a Top Slayer.
You got it, bud.
Hiccup.
I was only trying to protect you.
I know, Dad.
Let me return the favor.
Whatever happens up there
I'm proud to call you my son.
And that's all I need.
Let's go.
He's up!
You two get Snotlout.
I'll distract the queen.
That's right. Eyes on me.
Snotlout!
Now!
Oh, you have gotta be kidding me.
I can't believe that worked.
Yeah.
No, no, no, girl.
Fight it! Don't listen to her!
Shake it off!
Astrid.
Did you get her?
Go.
That thing has wings.
Let's see if it can use them.
You think that did it?
Yep.
All right, bud.
It's time to disappear.
Here it comes!
Quite the chief you have
in the making there.
Aye.
Watch out!
Okay, time's up.
Let's see if this works.
Is that all you've got?
Stay with me, bud!
Just a little bit longer!
Hold, Toothless!
Now!
Yeah, bud, we... No!
Hiccup!
Hiccup?
Son?
Hiccup!
Oh, son.
I'm so sorry.
Hiccup.
He's alive.
He's alive!
Yeah!
Yes!
Thank you...
for saving my son.
Well, you know, most of him.
Hey, Toothless.
Okay.
I'm in my house.
You're in my house.
Does my dad know you're here?
Come on.
Thanks, bud.
Okay, here we go.
Toothless, stay.
Hey! Shouldn't you be in bed?
Okay. Hold on tight, guys.
Here we go.
Hey! Hey! There you go!
- There he is!
- Okay.
So, what do you think?
A few changes since you've been out.
Flying back here was
quite an experience
- let me tell you.
- Wait, wait, you...
you rode a dragon?
Well... Well, that monster burned
all of our ships, so...
- Hiccup!
- we didn't really have much of a...
Oh, no. What'd I do this time?
- Ow!
- That's for scaring me.
Okay, is it always gonna
be like this? 'Cause--
And that's for everything else.
You know, 'cause...
'cause I... I could get used to that.
Yep.
Turns out all we needed
was a little more of this.
You just gestured to all of me.
Well, you know, most of ya.
New leg is my handiwork
with just a dash of your kooky flair
thrown in for good measure.
Here we go. Welcome home.
- You rebuilt it?
- Yeah.
I found your designs.
Not too bad.
Night Fury!
- Here he is.
- What is it?
What is it, huh?
Want to take it for a spin?
This is Berk.
You'd have to be crazy to move here.
Even crazier to stay.
It's not for the faint of heart.
Any food that grows here
is tough and tasteless.
Come on!
The people that grow here
are even more so.
The only upsides are the pets.
While other places may have
ponies or puppies...
Come on, bud.
we have...
dragons.